[{
        "question": "Ecology deals with the study of",
        "answers": { "A": "Living Beings", "B": "Living and non-living components", "C": "Reciprocal relationship between living and non-living components", "D": "Environment" },
        "correctAnswer": "C"
    }, {
        "question": "Energy flow in ecosystem is",
        "answers": { "A": "Unidirectional", "B": "Bidirectional", "C": "Multidirectional", "D": "None of the above" },
        "correctAnswer": "A"
    }, {
        "question": "The source of energy in an ecosystem is",
        "answers": { "A": "ATP", "B": "Sunlight", "C": "DNA", "D": "RNA" },
        "correctAnswer": "C"
    }, {
        "question": "Definition of ecosystem is",
        "answers": { "A": "The community of organisms togather with the environment in which they live", "B": "The abiotic component of a habitat", "C": "The part of the earth and its atmosphere which inhibits living organisms", "D": "A community of organisms interacting with one another" },
        "correctAnswer": "A"
    }, {
        "question": "An association between two individuals or populations where both are benefitted and where neighter can survive without the other is",
        "answers": { "A": "Competition", "B": "Communalism", "C": "Mutualism", "D": "Protocoperation" },
        "correctAnswer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "The final stable community in an ecological succession is called the",
        "answers": { "A": "Final Community", "B": "Ultimate Community", "C": "Seral Community", "D": "Climax Community" },
        "correctAnswer": "D"
    },
    {
        "question": "A group of a individual of a plant or animal species, inhabiting a given area is called",
        "answers": { "A": "Biome", "B": "Population", "C": "Ecosystem", "D": "Community" },
        "correctAnswer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "Conservation within the natural habitat is",
        "answers": { "A": "Insitu conservation", "B": "Exitu conservation", "C": "Invivo conservation", "D": "Exvivo conservation" },
        "correctAnswer": "A"
    },
    {
        "question": "All are insitu conservation effort except",
        "answers": { "A": "National Parks", "B": "Sanctuaries", "C": "Biosphere Reserves", "D": "Zoo" },
        "correctAnswer": "D"
    },
    {
        "question": "Conservation outside the natural habitat is",
        "answers": { "A": "Insitu conservation", "B": "Exitu conservation", "C": "Invivo conservation", "D": "Exvivo conservation" },
        "correctAnswer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the animal symbol of W.W.F.(World Wildlife Fund)",
        "answers": { "A": "Red Panda", "B": "Giant Panda", "C": "Tiger", "D": "Kangaroo" },
        "correctAnswer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "THe cutting down of tree is termed as",
        "answers": { "A": "Forestation", "B": "Plantation", "C": "Deforestation", "D": "Biodiversity" },
        "correctAnswer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "The natural place of an organism or community is known as",
        "answers": { "A": "Niche", "B": "Biome", "C": "Habitat", "D": "Habit" },
        "correctAnswer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "The organisms that live on organic materials and absorb organic molecules by digesting enzymes are called",
        "answers": { "A": "Decomposers", "B": "Producers", "C": "Carnivores", "D": "Omnivores" },
        "correctAnswer": "A"
    },
    {
        "question": "Plants are also regarded as",
        "answers": { "A": "Flora", "B": "Fauna", "C": "Flower", "D": "Botany" },
        "correctAnswer": "A"
    }
]
